Matthew Padich

Full Stack Engineer - Settle Inc

- Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Matthew-Padich/e80a0541884c7184

I am a web developer working towards becoming a qualified full stack engineer. I am very familiar with JS, modern HTML5 / CSS3 standards and frameworks, PHP, WordPress, and all the build tools required in order to create modern SPA's and great looking static web pages. Lately I have been working on a variety of projects, most notably I have built a .NET application from the ground up for a startup and I have worked on functional programming concepts with a personal web project written in Elm. I am very interested in functional programming and learning about new technologies that will shape the future of the web.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer

Settle Inc - April 2017 to Present

Currently the sole engineer building out a peer to peer payment application via the Dwolla API. Set up back and front end build, continuous integration with Azure web services, designed our internal APIs, continue to style and maintain brand image for our application which is currently in beta.

- Built on .NETCore1.1, C# 7.0, Visual Studio dev tools for Mac. Deployed for beta testing to Azure.
- Handle everything from performance and DB maintenance to front end architecture. I field questions and concern for copy, design, and tech on a daily basis.

Web Developer

Elite Daily - July 2015 to April 2017

Handled all things front-end and WordPress related on the dotcom. Ads and Analytics (Google AdWords, DFP, Google Analytics), Newsletters (integration with MailChimp API), site performance (conditional script loading, prefetch, mobile optimized code, reduced TTFP ~70% in coordination with our backend team), creating new templates and styles for internal campaigns and one off pages, and created CMS tools to allow for custom content on the site.

- Helped build an internal analytics tool that incorporated share / social data from Facebook, Instagram, and YouTube APIs. Built the front end of the app in React.js sitting on top of SlimPHP. Helped ads and editorial to see how content was performing and how we could improve our user reach and interaction.
- Contributed to the Elite Daily iOS app. Helped write unit tests, maintain code readability, and build out web views that interacted with our internal content API's.

Web Developer

Fortune.com - September 2014 to July 2015

Set up the front-end build for the site, configured tools for running unit and end to end tests, modularized our Marionette.js codebase, and optimized our CSS and JS footprint.

Built the Fortune 500 application from the ground up with one other senior JS developer. Integrated interactive
ads, graphs (d3.js), and other branded content across the SPA. Learned the do's and (mostly) don'ts of
structuring large scale production ready and mobile friendly MVC applications.

EDUCATION

BA in Philosophy / Religion

Hofstra University

Ward Melville HS

2006

SKILLS

API (2 years), IOS (1 year), CSS (Less than 1 year), AJAX (Less than 1 year), AWS (Less than 1 year)

LINKS

https://github.com/mattyfresh

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills

Advanced

- * JS jQuery, Backbone / Marionette.js, ES6/7, AJAX, JSON
- * PHP WordPress, PHP7
- * Tools/Misc. Jenkins, Virtual Box, Vagrant, Gulp / Grunt, xCode, webpagetest.org, Chrome / Safari dev tools, BrowserStack, Google Analytics, Dwolla, Facebook API, Babel, Browserify
- * HTML/CSS CSS preprocessors like Scss and Sass, HTML5 spec, web page accessibility for visually impaired persons, HTML forms

Competent

- * JS React, Redux architecture, TypeScript, Node.js, Angular, Polymer web components
- * PHP OOP, SlimPHP, Cake
- * Tools/Misc. webpack, CircleCi, MongoDB, web workers, New Relic, AWS Web Services, MySQL, bash, oAuth2
- * .NET/C# OOP, dependency injection, MV* style application via Entity Framework Casual
- * iOS/OSx Swift 3, core data, Carthage, CocoaPods, storyboard visualizer
- * Elm Elm 1.8, Union Types, routing, JSON parsing, functional programming techniques (map, reduce, immutability)